Hey everybody, welcome
to the content video
going over section 4.7, the math module.
So in this video, we kind of
branch out a little bit from
the last topic we covered,
which was the random module.
The math module is another
library in Python that you
can import into your code that
has a whole host of functions
that you can borrow. And
what are those functions?
Wow, I'm so glad that you asked.
Here are a summary of the
different functions that are
within the math module. So they
are extremely helpful so that
you don't have to code some
more complex math by hand.
Somebody has already done that
and so they're all contained right
here. We've got functions like
ceiling, floor, sine, cosine, tangent,
exponential,
log, log 10, power, square root,
fabs which oh absolute value float
absolute value and f mod which is
a floating point um remainder so uh
rather than show you every single
one of these we'll just go ahead and
do a demo a quick one of just like
maybe one or two of them so let's
do import math and then let's bar
let's do square root and power so
um and if you ever want to read more
about how these work they've got
examples of how you would use them
here so like power takes two
arguments and square root takes one so
for example let's say print uh math
dot square root of 144 and we'll
also print math math.pow of 2 and
5, and let's see what those give us,
12 and 32. So, 2 raised
to the fifth power and the
square root of 144. So,
that's kind of like a
quick summary and introduction
to the math module.
If you're doing things in your
code that might need some more
complicated math, this is a great
way to explore those without
necessarily getting too bogged
down with writing up complete
statement or like complete math
for like solving it all yourself.
Anyways, that's all for this
content video. Thanks for watching.